A Day in a Coastal Village A multitude of visitors gathered on
the fringe of the village as milky light spread across the bay
Boats moved to and fro and a path along the hill's flank
led to the shore The morning seemed pacific yet a notice warned
us to beware of changing weather At noon a swell appeared offshore
Guides asked people to disperse except for a group waiting under shelter
One visitor called the precaution senseless Presumably he expected calm weather to
last on the contrary the guide had received an updated forecast We
went indoors to hear local history Our host used plague to mean
a recurring problem not a current illness The story helped kindle curiosity
A frightful event showed how people could perish without community support Responsible
travel begins with listening to people who know a place